(Interpreter voice-over) Hello, everyone. My name is Keith Nolan.
(صوت المترجمة الفورية) مرحبًا للجميع، اسمي كيث نولان.
I’m a cadet private.
أنا جندي بالعكسرية
My talk today is on the topic of the military.
حديثي اليوم عن موضوع العسكرية
How many of you out there thought you’d ever like to join the military?
كم منكم اعتقد أنه لن ينضم إلى العسكرية أبدًا؟
I see a number of you nodding.
أرى عددًا منكم يومأ برأسه
And I thought the same thing ever since I was young.
واعتقدتُ نفس الشيء منذ كنتُ صغيرًا.
Growing up, I’d always wanted to join the military.
وكبرتُ وأنا أرغبُ دومًا في الالتحاق بالعسكرية
I loved military history
أحب التاريخ العسكري
and I’ve read a great deal on the subject.
وقرأتُ الكثير عن هذا الموضوع.
Also, I have various family members, such as my grandfather and great uncle,
لدي أيضًا العديد من أفراد الأسرة مثل جدي وعمي الأكبر،
who fought in World War II.
الذين حاربوا في الحرب العالمية الثانية.
And like them, I wanted the same thing: to serve my country.
وأردتُ مثلهم نفس الشيء: أن أخدم وطني.
So the question is: Can I?
لذا فالسؤال هو: هل أستطيع؟
No, I can’t.
لا، لا أستطيع.
Why? Simply because I’m deaf.
لماذا؟ لأنني ببساطة أصم.
Regardless of that fact, I still had that longing to join the military.
بغض النظر عن تلك الحقيقة، لا يزالُ لدي ذلك الشوق للالتحاق بالعسكرية.
For example, after I graduated from high school,
مثلًا، بعدما تخرجت من المدرسة الثانوية،
three months before 9/11 occurred,
قبل ثلاثة أشهر من أحداث 11 أيلول/سبتمبر،
I went to a naval recruiting center with high hopes of joining the navy.
ذهبت إلى مركز التجنيد البحري بآمال عالية أن ألتحق بالبحرية.
I went in and a strapping naval man stood up and addressed me.
دخلتُ ونهض رجل قوي من البحرية وخاطبني.
As he was speaking to me, it was impossible for me to read his lips,
بينما كان يكلمني، كان من المستحيل علي أن أقرأ شفاهه،
so I said, “I'm sorry, I’m deaf.”
فقلت "أنا آسف، أنا أصم".
He tore off a little piece of paper and wrote down three words:
مزق ورقة صغيرة وكتب ثلاث كلمات:
“Bad ear. Disqual.”
"أذن عاطلة، غير مؤ."
He didn't even fully spell out "Disqualified,"
حتى لم ينطق كاملًا "غير مؤهل"،
just: “Bad ear. Disqual.”
فقط "أذن عاطلة.غير مؤ".
So I went on my way.
فذهبت في طريقي.
I tried various locations a number of different times, trying to join,
جربت أماكن عدة في مرات مختلفة محاولًا الالتحاق،
but over and over again, I got the same response:
وكنتُ أتلقى نفس الرد مرارًا وتكرارًا:
“Sorry, you’re deaf. We can’t accept you.”
"المعذرة! أنت أصم. لا نستطيع قبولك".
So I shifted gears and decided to become a teacher.
لذلك غيرتُ مساري، وقررت أن أصبح معلمًا.
I completed a master's in deaf education and taught for almost two years,
أكملتُ شهادة الماجستير في تعليم الصم، وعلمتُ لسنتين تقريبًا.
until this past spring, when three things occurred
حتى الربيع الماضي، عندما حدثت ثلاثة أشياء
that changed that course,
غيرت ذلك المسار،
the first of which, while I was teaching a high school history class.
أولها، عندما كنت أُدرّس حصة التاريخ في المدرسة الثانوية
I’d lectured on the Mexican-American War.
ألقيتُ محاضرة عن الحرب المكسيكية الأمريكية.
The bell had rung, and I was seated at my desk,
رن الجرس، وكنت جالسًا على مكتبي،
when one of my students, who is deaf, approached me
عندما اقترب واحد من تلاميدي الذي هو أصم،
and said that he’d like to join the military.
وقال أنه يتمنى الالتحاق بالعسكرية.
I said, “Ah, sorry. You can’t. You're deaf.”
قلت،"آه ، آسف. لا تستطيع. أنت أصم".
Then I caught myself.
ثم تمالكتُ نفسي.
It struck me that all along I had been told no, I can’t,
قد استوقفني ذلك منذ وقتٍ طويل عندما قيل لي لا، لا أستطيع
and now I was perpetuating that same message
وكنتُ أبقي على تلك الرسالة نفسها
to the next generation, to my own student.
للجيل القادم، لتلميذي.
That realization had a large impact that really resonated with me.
كان لذلك الإدراك تأثير كبير مما ترك صدى بالنسبة لي حقًا.
Now, the second thing that happened, my friend had just moved to Israel.
الآن، الشيء الثاني الذي حدث، انتقال صديقي لتوه إلى إسرائيل.
Did you know that in Israel they accept deaf people into the military?
هل تعلمون أنهم يقبلون الصم في الجيش في إسرائيل؟
How can deaf people be in the military, right?
كيف يمكنُ للصُم أن يكونوا في الجيش، أليس كذلك؟
Could this really be true? Come on!
هل يمكن أن يكون ذلك صحيحًا؟ لا أصدق!
Well, I went to Israel last summer to see for myself.
حسنا، ذهبت لإسرائيل الصيف الفائت لأرى بنفسي.
I interviewed 10 deaf Israeli soldiers,
قابلت عشرة جنود إسرائيليين صُم،
all of those video interviews and questions I’ve compiled,
وجمعت فيديوهات وأسئلة هذه المقابلات،
and the findings, I’ll share with you later.
وسأشارككم النتائج لاحقًا.
Thirdly, CSUN here, my alma mater,
ثالثًا، جامعة ولاية كاليفورنيا/نورثريدج (CSUN)، جامعتي الأم،
had recently started up an Army ROTC program.
بدأت مؤخرًا برنامجًا عسكريًا يدعى هيئة تدريب ضباط الاحتياط (ROTC)
ROTC, which stands for Reserve Officer Training Corps,
(ROTC) ترمز إلى: هيئة تدريب ضباط الاحتياط،
allows students working on their college majors
تسمحُ للطلاب للعمل في تخصصاتهم الرئيسة
to concurrently participate in the ROTC program.
وفي نفس الوقت المشاركة في برنامج هيئة تدريب ضباط الاحتياط.
Upon graduation, ROTC students have a military career
بعد تخرجهم، يكون لدى طلبة برنامج هيئة تدريب ضباط الاحتياط مهنة عسكرية
ready and waiting for them.
جاهزة وبانتظارهم.
So if one joined the army, one could commission as a second lieutenant.
فإذا التحق أحدهم بالجيش، يمكن ترقيته لمرتبة ملازم ثانٍ
That's generally the ROTC program here at CSUN.
هذا هو برنامج (ROTC) في جامعة ولاية كاليفورنيا/نورثريدج.
Having learned that, I was intrigued.
وأثير فضولي بعد معرفتي ذلك.
I already had a profession as a teacher,
كانت مهنتي أصلًا كمدرس،
but I went ahead anyway and sent an email off to the program,
ومضيتُ قدمًا وبعثتُ برسالة إلكترونية إلى البرنامج،
explaining that I was a teacher of the deaf,
موضحًا بأنني كنت مدرسًا للصُم،
wondering if I could take a few classes with them
متسائلًا إذا كان بإمكاني أخذ عدة فصول معهم
and perhaps share their lessons with my students.
وربما مشاركة دروسهم مع طلابي.
I got an email response back,
وتلقيتُ ردًا بالبريد الإلكتروني،
and surprisingly, it was the first time that I wasn't told,
ويالها من مفاجأة، لأول مرة لا يقالُ لي،
"Sorry, no, you can’t. You’re deaf."
"المعذرة! لا، لا تستطيع. أنت أصم."
It said, "Well, that's interesting.
ذُكر فيها، "حسنا، هذا مثير للاهتمام.
I think maybe we can work something out
أعتقدُ قد يمكننا فعل شيء تجاه هذا الأمر
and you can take a few classes with us."
ويمكنك أخذ عدة فصول معنا".
This was unprecedented.
كان هذا غير مسبوق.
So naturally, I was shocked.
بطبيعة الحال، كنت مصدومًا.
Although I was teaching, I decided I had to grab the opportunity right away
علي الرغم من أني ما زلت مدرسًا، إلا أنني قررت اغتنام الفرصة في الحال
and get my foot in the door.
وأن أخطو الخطوة الأولى نحو الطريق
Altogether, that's how it transpired.
هكذا سارت الأحداث تمامًا.
Now, with all my life experiences,
الآن، مع كل خبرات حياتي،
having talked with all the people I had, and given everything I’ve read,
بعد أن قابلتُ كل الأشخاص الذين أعرفهم، وإعطاء كل شيء قرأته،
I decided to write a research paper called “Deaf in the Military.”
قررت كتابة ورقة بحثية بعنوان "أصم في العسكرية".
I'll share with you what those 98 pages entail.
سأشاركم ما انطوت عليه هذه الصفحات البالغ عددها 98 صفحة.
Here in America, we’ve actually had deaf soldiers serving in the past.
هنا في أمريكا، كان لدينا بالفعل الجنود الصُم الذين خدموا في الماضي.
In fact, during the Texas War of Independence,
في الواقع، أثناء حرب استقلال تكساس،
there was a key character named Deaf Smith,
كان هناك شخصية محورية تدعى سميث الأصم،
who made a large contribution to that war effort.
الذي ساهم بشكل كبير في المجهود الحربي.
For the American Civil War,
وفي الحرب الأمريكية الأهلية،
Gallaudet University actually has archived a list of deaf soldiers in that war
احتفظت جامعة جالوديت بسجل يحوي قائمة الجنود الصم في تلك الحرب.
from the North and the South,
من الجنوب والشمال،
showing that deaf soldiers were even fighting against each other.
تظهرُ أن الجنود الصم كانوا حتى يحاربون ضد بعضهم البعض.
During World War II, there are a few rare examples
أثناء الحرب العالمية الثانية، هناك بعض النماذج النادرة
of deaf people who made it into the military at that time
من الصم الذين التحقوا بالعسكرية في هذا الوقت
and were able to serve their country as well.
وكانوا قادرين على خدمة وطنهم كذلك.
History illustrates the fact that America has had deaf soldiers,
يوضحُ التاريخ الحقيقة أنه كان لدى أمريكا الجنود الصم
in contrast to today.
على العكس من اليوم.
In my paper, I also discuss the deaf Israeli soldiers.
في ورقتي، أناقشُ أيضًا الجنود الإسرائيلين الصُم
I learned that they serve in non-combat roles.
علمت أنهم يخدمون في وظائف غير قتالية.
The deaf soldiers are not on the front lines engaged in fire,
ليس الجنود الصم في الصفوف الأمامية يشاركون في إطلاق النار،
but rather, are behind the lines serving in supportive roles.
ولكن في الخطوط الخلفية يخدمون في أدوارٍ داعمة.
There are a plethora of various non-combat jobs accessible to the deaf:
هناك عدد لا يحصى من الوظائف غير القتالية المختلفة المتاحة للصم:
intelligence, computer technology, map drawing, supply,
المخابرات وتكنولوجيا الحاسوب ورسم الخرائط والإمدادات
military dog training --
وتدريب الكلاب العسكرية
the list goes on.
وتطول القائمة.
The communication between deaf Israeli soldiers
التواصل بين الجنود الإسرائيلين الصُم
and other soldiers who are hearing
وغيرهم من الجنود الذين يسمعون
is carried out with the same approaches deaf people in general use
يتم بنفس الوسائل التي يستخدمها الصم بشكل عام
with the hearing public on a daily basis.
مع عامة الناس الذين يسمعون بصورة يومية.
You can use your voice, lip-read, gestures,
يمكنكم استخدام صوتكم وقراءة الشفاه والإيماءات
sometimes another soldier knows sign language and that can be utilized,
يعرفُ جندي آخر في بعض الأحيان لغة الإشارة التي يمكن استخدامها،
pen and paper, texts, computers, emails --
أقلام وأوراق، رسائل نصية، حواسيب ورسائل إلكترونية ...
seriously, there’s no magic wand necessary.
بجد، لا يلزمُ الأمر عصا سحرية.
It's the same thing we do every day.
إنها نفس الأشياء التي نفعلها كل يوم.
Interpreters are used there primarily for boot camp training.
يستخدمُ المترجمون أساسًا في تدريبات اللياقة البدنية.
For the average work, it’s not necessary to have an interpreter by your side.
للعمل العادي، لا يوجد حاجة لمترجم بجانبكم
The Israeli Army is comprised of small groups.
يتكون الجيش الإسرائيلي من مجموعات صغيرة.
Each of these units with deaf soldiers have developed
طورت كل من هذه الوحدات التي لديها جنود صُم
their own way of communicating with each other,
طريقتها الخاصة للتواصل مع بعضهم البعض،
so there’s no need for interpreters.
لذلك لا توجد حاجة لمترجمين.
The top picture is of one soldier I met.
الصورة العليا لجندي قابلته.
The bottom photo is of Prime Minister Begin
والصورة السفلى لرئيس الوزراء بيجن
with a deaf soldier in Israel.
مع جندي أصم في إسرائيل.
Another part of my paper touches on disabled soldiers in the US Military.
يلقي جزء آخر من ورقتي الضوء على الجنود ذوي الإعاقة في العسكرية الأمريكية
Obviously, military work can be dangerous and involve injury.
من الواضح، يمكن للعمل العسكري أن يكون خطيرًا ويتضمن إصابات.
One example here is Captain Luckett.
أحد الأمثلة هنا هو النقيب لوسيت.
Due to an explosion, he lost his leg.
فقد ساقه بسبب انفجار.
He’s recovered and currently has a prosthetic leg.
لقد تعافى ولديه الآن ساق اصطناعية.
Now that he’s strong, he's back in combat, still fighting in Afghanistan.
لقد تعافي الآن وعاد إلى ساحة القتال ولا يزال يقاتل في أفغانستان.
It’s remarkable.
هذا رائع.
And guess what? He’s not the only one.
واحزروا ماذا؟ أنه ليس الوحيد.
There are 40 other soldiers like him,
هناك 40 جنديًاآخر مثله،
amputees who are serving in combat zones.
مبتوري الأطراف يخدمون في مناطق القتال.
Incredible.
لا يصدق.
Also, we have a blind soldier here.
ولدينا أيضًا جندي كفيف هنا.
While he was in Iraq,
بينما كان في العراق،
an explosion from a suicide car bomber destroyed his eyesight.
قضى انفجار قنبلة في سيارة يقودها انتحاري على بصره.
He’s recovered and hasn’t left the army.
لقد تعافى ولم يترك الجيش.
The army has retained him on active duty,
استعان به الجيش في الخدمة الفعلية،
and he’s currently running a hospital for wounded soldiers.
وهو الآن يدير مستشفى للجنود الجرحى.
I also found out online about another soldier,
كما وجدت أيضًا عبر الإنترنت جنديًا آخر
who is deaf in one ear.
أصم في أذن واحدة.
He’s developed civil programs in Iraq,
طور برامج مدنية في العراق،
one of which actually started a school for the deaf in Iraq.
أنشأ واحدًا منها في الواقع مدرسة للصم في العراق.
All of this is incredible.
كل هذا لا يصدق.
But I am going to ask all of you:
لكني سوف أسألكم جميعًا:
If the US Military can retain their disabled soldiers,
إذا استطاعت العسكرية الأمريكية الاستعانة بجنودها ذوي الإعاقة،
why can’t they accept disabled citizens as well?
لمَ لا يستطيعون قبول المواطنين ذوي الإعاقة أيضًا؟
Moreover, out of all the US Military jobs, 80% are non-combat positions.
علاوة علي ذلك، 80% من الوظائف العسكرية الأمريكية هي وظائف غير قتالية
There are many jobs that we in the Deaf community can do.
هناك الكثيرمن الوظائف التي يمكننا القيام بها كمجموعة من الصُم.
If I were to be in the military, I’d like to do intelligence work.
لو كنت في العسكرية، لوددت أن أعمل في المخابرات.
But there is an array of other things we can do,
لكن يوجد مجموعة من الأشياء الأخرى التي نستطيع القيام بها،
such as mechanics, finance, medicine, etc.
مثل الميكانيكا والمالية والطب، إلى آخره.
So to summarize, I’ve presented three premises to support my argument,
لكي أختصر، عرضت ثلاثة أماكن لدعم ادعائي،
the first being, Israeli defense openly accepts deaf soldiers.
الأول، يقبلُ الدفاع الإسرائيلي الجنود الصم بشكل علني.
If you have the qualities and skills required, they’ll take you.
إذا كان لدى أحدكم المؤهلات والمهارات المطلوبة، سيقبلونك.
Secondly, the US Military has accommodations
ثانيا، لدى العسكرية الأمريكية ترتيبات خاصة
for retaining their disabled soldiers.
للاستعانة بجنودها ذوي الإعاقة.
And lastly, 80% of occupations in the military are non-combat.
وأخيرًا، 80% من الوظائف العسكرية هي غير قتالية.
Now, can we Deaf Americans serve our country?
الآن، هل بإمكاننا نحن الصم الأمريكيين خدمة بلادنا؟
Yes! Of course! Absolutely, without a doubt!
أجل! بالتأكيد! بكل ما تحمل الكلمة من معنى، بلا شك!
Now I’ll explain a bit about my experience in the Army ROTC,
سأوضح الآن قليلًا عن تجربتي في جيش هيئة تدريب ضباط الاحتياط،
which began last fall.
التي بدأت الخريف الماضي.
I have been involved with that thus far and it’s still going on now.
لقد اشتركتُ فيها حتى الآن ولا تزال قائمة إلى الآن.
Really, I need to preface this
أحتاجُ حقًا أن أستغل هذه الفرصة
by saying that this is the first time my battalion had ever had a deaf cadet.
لأقول أنها المرة الأولى التي تحوي كتيبتي فيها على الإطلاق تلميذ أصم.
They had never experienced that before.
لم يسبق لهم تجربة ذلك من قبل.
So of course, they were taken aback, wondering, initially,
لذلك بالطبع كانوا مندهشين، وتساءلوا في البداية
how I would do this or that, how would we communicate and such,
كيف سأفعل هذا أو ذاك، وكيف سنتواصل وأشياء من هذ القبيل،
which is a natural reaction,
الذي هو رد فعل طبيعي،
considering that many of them had never interacted with a deaf person
باعتبار أنه لم يتعامل أغلبهم مع شخص أصم أبدًا.
prior to me.
قبلي.
Plus, I was taken aback by this -- it was the real thing, the army.
بالإضافة إلى ذلك، لقد دهشتُ بذلك ... لقد كان شيئًا حقيقيًا، الجيش.
I had to learn a whole new world, full of military jargon,
كان عليّ أن أتعلم عن عالم جديد تماما، مليء بالمصطلحات العسكرية،
with its own culture and everything.
بثقافته الخاصة وكل شيء.
So we started out slow, getting to know each other
لذلك بدأنا بالتعرف على بعضنا البعض ببطء
and learning how to work together, progressively.
وتعلمنا كيف نعمل معًا تدريجيًا.
For example, on the first day of class, I had no uniform.
علي سبيل المثال، في يومي الأول في الفصل، لم يكن لدي زي موحد.
So I showed up in regular clothes,
لذلك ظهرتُ في ملابسي العادية،
while the other cadets were all in uniform.
بينما كان باقي الطلاب في زيهم الموحد.
I found out that every morning at 5:30, there was physical training, PT.
وجدت أنه وفي كل صباح عند الساعة 5:30، يوجد تدريب بدني (PT).
On Fridays, there would be field training -- labs -- off-campus,
في أيام الجمعة، يوجد تدريبات ميدانية... مختبرات ... خارج الحرم الجامعي،
and occasionally, we would have weekend training at a military base.
ويكون لدينا أحيانًا تدريبيات في نهاية الأسبوع في القواعد العسكرية.
So I showed up, ready, each morning at 5:30,
لذلك كنت أظهر مستعدًا كل صباح في 5:30،
with all the cadets in uniform and me in civilian clothes.
مع كل الطلاب في زيهم الموحد وأنا في ملابسي المدنية.
They told me, “Hey, you know, you don't need to work out.
لقد أخبروني،"أتعلم، لستَ بحاجة إلى تدريب بدني.
You can just simply take classes.”
تستطيع ببساطة أخذ فصولك الدراسية فقط."
I told them I wanted to, anyway.
أخبرتهم برغبتي في التدريب البدني مع ذلك.
They acknowledged that, and I continued to show up every morning to train.
أقروا بذلك، واستمريتُ في ظهوري كل صباح للتدريب.
When Friday came, I asked if I could do the field training.
وعندما جاء يوم الجمعة، سألت إن أمكن مشاركتي في التدريب الميداني.
I was told no, just stick with class.
وكانت الإجابة بالرفض، علىّ الالتزام بالفصل فقط.
I insisted that I wanted to try.
أصررت أني أريد المحاولة.
Somewhat reluctantly, they let me attend the lab,
وبتردد إلى حدٍ ما، سمحوا لي بحضور المختبر،
but only as an observer;
لكن كمراقب فقط،
I would only be allowed to sit and watch, not participate.
سوف يسمحُ لي فقط أن أجلس وأشاهد، لا أن أشارك.
Alright, so, I showed up on Friday,
حسنا، لقد ظهرت في يوم الجمعة،
and watched as the cadets learned marching drill commands,
شاهدت الطلاب يتلقون أوامر تدريب الزحف،
like how to stand at attention, how to properly salute,
مثل كيفية الوقوف بانتباه، وكيفية التحية العسكرية بشكل صحيح،
and all the basics.
وكل هذه الأساسيات.
I had to ask again if I could join.
كان علي أن أسأل مجددًا عن إمكانية انضمامي.
Finally, I got the go-ahead.
أخيرًا، نُلت الموافقة.
I went to get in formation.
ذهبت لأكون في التشكيل.
I figured I better stand in the second line,
اكتشفتُ من الأفضل الوقوف في الصف الثاني،
so I could watch what the cadets were doing in the row ahead of me.
حتي يمكنني رؤية ما يقوم به الطلاب في الصف أمامي
But the officer who opened the door for me to join the ROTC program
لكن الضابط المسؤول الذي فتح لي الباب للالتحاق ببرنامج هيئة تدريب ضباط الاحتياط
spotted me in the back and said, “Hey! Uh-uh. I want you in the front.
رآني في الخلف وقال، "مهلاً! أنت! أريدك بالمقدمة.
You want to be a soldier?
تريد أن تصبح جنديًا؟
You've got to learn the commands just like the rest of them.
يجب أن تتعلم تنفيذ الأوامر كبقيتهم تمامًا.
I thought, "Wow.
فكرت، "يا للروعة!
He’s viewing me like any person, giving dignity to who I am."
أنه يراني كأي شخص عادي ويمنحني الكرامة لما أنا عليه."
I was impressed by that.
كنت منبهرًا بذلك.
So as the weeks went by, I still didn’t have a uniform.
ومع مرور الأسابيع، ما زلتُ دون زي موحد.
I asked if it would be possible to get one, but I was told it wasn't.
سألت إذا أمكنني الحصول علي واحد، ولكن كان الرد بالنفي.
So I continued on that way,
لذلك استمريت على هذا النهج.
until one day, I was informed that I’d be getting a uniform.
حتي ذات اليوم، عندما اخبرت أني سأحصل على زي موحد.
"Please!" I said, “Really? Why? What changed?”
قلت، "من فضلك!""حقا؟ لماذا؟ ماذا طرأ؟".
I was told, “We see your motivation, you show up every morning, dedicated,
أُخبرت، " نحن نرى حماسك، كنت تأتي كل صباح بإخلاصٍ
and always gave a 110% effort.”
وتقدمُ دائمًا مجهودًا بنسبة 110%".
They wanted to give me the uniform.
أرادوا منحي الزي الموحد.
It was remarkable.
لقد كان ذلك رائعًا!
We went to the warehouse to get my uniform.
ذهبنا للمستودع لاستلام زيي الموحد.
I assumed I’d just get a uniform and a pair of boots, nothing more.
افترضت أني سأحصل فقط علي الزي وزوج من الأحذية لا أكثر.
But they filled two duffel bags chock-full of gear:
لكنهم ملأوا حقيبتين مصنوعتين من الصوف الخشن بالمعدات:
helmet, ammo vest, shovel, sleeping bag -- the whole nine yards.
خوذة وسترة حمل الذخائر، وجاروف وحقيبة للنوم، العدة كاملة.
I was astonished.
كنت مبهورًا.
And I have to tell you,
وعلي إخباركم،
each morning that I get up and put on my uniform,
كل صباح أستيقظ وأرتدي الزي العسكري،
I feel privileged.
أشعر بالتميز.
It’s truly an honor to wear the uniform.
إنه لشرفُ حقًا ارتداء الزي العسكري.
So, moving along,
ولكي نمضي قدمًا،
when it came time to train at the garrison base,
عندما جاء موعد التدريب في قاعدة الحامية العسكرية،
at first, I was told I couldn’t go.
في البداية، أُخبرت أنه لا يمكنني الذهاب.
There was concern on the ROTC's part
كانت هناك قلقًا من جانب هيئة تدريب ضباط الاحتياط
that if the interpreter were to get injured during the training,
أنه لو حصل وأصيب المترجم أثناء التدريب،
it would be a liability issue.
سيكون هناك قضية مساءلة قانونية.
So we had to figure out all those issues and confusion,
لذلك كان علينا حل كل هذه القضايا والإشكاليات،
but we worked it out, and in the end, they let me go.
لكننا حللنا المشكلة، وسمحوا لي بالذهاب في النهاية.
That's how events were unfolding; I was permitted to do more and more.
هكذا تطورت الأحداث، وسمح لي بفعل المزيد والمزيد.
Once, at the garrison base, during one of the training days,
ذات مرة، وفي قادة الحامية العسكرية أثناء أحد أيام التدريب،
a huge Chinook helicopter with its tandem rotors landed right down to us,
هبطت طائرة عمودية ضخمة من نوع تشينوك `ذات الدوارات الترادفية أمامنا مباشرة،
forcefully spinning exhilaration in the air.
كانت تدور بقوة مخلخلة ما حولها من هواء.
All of us cadets were supposed to be getting on board.
كان على كل الطلاب الصعود على متنها.
Everyone was geared up and ready.
تأهب واستعد الجميع،
However, the cadre had decided
مع ذلك، قرر الكادر
I wasn’t going to be able to ride the Chinook.
لن أكون قادرًا على ركوب طائرة تشينوك.
They were afraid if the pilot shouted out orders,
خافوا إذا صاح الطيار معطيًا أوامره،
how would I be able to follow the instructions?
كيف سأكون قادرًا على اتباع تعليماته؟
I’d potentially cause a disruption.
من المحتمل أن أسبب تشتيتًا.
So I had to stand aside,
لذلك كان علي أن أتنحي جانبًا،
while the others were filing toward the helicopter.
بينما كان الآخرون يتقدمون نحو الطائرة.
I could see the cadre huddled up, discussing, mulling it over.
أمكنني رؤية الكادر تجتمعُ وتناقش، وتدرس الأمر.
At the last minute, one of them said, “Come on! Get on the helicopter!”
وفي آخر دقيقة، قال أحدهم، "هيا! اصعد إلى الطائرة العمودية!"
I rushed over and got in. It was such a thrill.
اندفعت ودخلتها. كانت لحظة مليئة بالتشويق.
And that was the spirit of learning about and supporting one another
وكانت تلك هي روح معرفة ودعم بعضنا البعض
that carried over.
والتي سيطرت على الأجواء.
And since then, I’ve been involved in everything they do,
ومن يومها، اشتركت في كل ما يفعلوه،
This is where my passion lies.
هنا حيثُ يكمنُ شغفي.
I love them. I’ll show you some pictures here.
أنا أحبهم. سأريكم بعض الصور هنا.
Bruin Battalion, Bravo Company -- that’s the name of the group I belong to.
بروين بتاليون، سرية برافو، هذا هو اسم المجموعة التي أنتمي إليها.
The cadre are the officers and sergeants who oversee the ROTC program.
الكادر هم الضباط والرقباء الذين يشرفون على برنامج هيئة تدريب ضباط الاحتياط.
In the beginning, you can see, it was a bit of an awkward phase.
في البداية، وكما ترون، كانت مرحلة صعبة قليلًا.
But once they learned more about me and what I’m capable of doing,
لكن عندما عرفوني أكثر، وعرفوا ما يمكنني القيام به،
there's been tremendous support and unity.
كان هناك دعم واتحاد هائلين.
The cadets, my fellow peers -- well, when you train and sweat together,
الطلبة، زملائي، عندما تتمرنون وتعرقون معا،
you feel the bond of camaraderie right away.
تشعر برابطة الصداقة الحميمة .
A brother- or sisterly cohesiveness makes them like family.
ترابط الأخ أو الأخت الذي يجعلهم كعائلة.
In training and military science classes, we learn theories of warfare,
في التدريبات وفصول العلوم العسكرية، تعلمنا نظريات الحرب،
how to lead soldiers, how to do reconnaissance,
كيف نقود الجنود، وكيف نستطلع،
strategies, how to knock out a bunker
ونضع الخطط، وكيف نشق طريقنا في الخندق
and land navigation, where you’re finding your way out in the mountains.
ونتنقل في البر حيث نجد طريقنا في الجبال.
As far as accommodations, I’ve been provided with interpreters
وفيما يخص أماكن الإقامة، تم تزويدي بمترجمين
through the National Center on Deafness, NCOD, here at CSUN.
من خلال المركزي القومي للصم (NCOD)، هنا في جامعة ولاية كاليفورنيا/نورثريدج.
And I really have to thank them,
وعلي حقا شكرهم،
because it's hard to find interpreters
لأنه من الصعب إيجاد مترجمين
who are willing to wake up at 4:30 in the morning,
يرغبون في الاستيقاظ عند 4:30 صباحًا.
or sometimes even 3:30 in the morning.
أو حتى أحيانًا عند 3:30 صباحًا.
That's the officer who emailed me back,
هذا هو الضابط الذي بعث رسالة في البريد الإلكتروني،
saying I think you can have a few classes with us.
قائلًا أعتقدُ أنه بإمكانك أخذ عدة فصول معنا.
That's Lieutenant Mendoza.
هذا هو الملازم مينودزا.
That’s my interpreter there, before class starts.
هذا هو مترجمي هناك قبل أن يبدأ الدرس.
This is a picture from last fall, when we were new to training.
هذه الصورة من الخريف الماضي عندما كنا مستجدين في التدريب.
This is Lieutenant Colonel Phelps,
هذا هو الملازم العقيد فيليبس،
this being his name sign.
هذه هي إشارة اسمه.
He's the commanding officer of the entire Bruin Battalion.
إنه الضابط المسؤول الآمر لكتيبة بروين بتاليون كاملةً.
Every time I see him walk by, it’s rather inspiring.
كلما مر بجانبي أشعر بالإلهام.
I mean, the way he presents himself, you can see he’s the epitome of a soldier.
أعني من الطريقة التي يقدم بها نفسه يمكنك أن ترى المثال الحق للجندي.
Plus, he doesn't view me as a deaf person.
إلى جانب، أنه لا يراني كشخص أصم.
He looks at my skills and capabilities instead.
ولكنه ينظر إلى مهاراتي وقدراتي بدلا عن ذلك.
He’s really pushed for me, and I respect him for all that.
لقد دعمني حقًا، وأنا أحترمه لكل ذلك.
That’s me during one of the exercises.
هذا أنا أثناء أحد التدريبات.
This is that Chinook helicopter I almost didn’t get on.
هذه هي طائرة تشينوك التي كنتُ على وشك عدم الصعود إليها.
Every cadet has a mentor.
لدى كل طالب موجّه.
My mentor is Cinatl.
موجهي هو سينتال.
He’s a really sharp soldier.
إنه جندي حاذق حقًا.
He teaches me all the finer points and how to execute them ideally.
كان يعلمني كل التفصيلات الصغيرة، وكيفية تنفيذها بشكل مثالي.
This top picture is when a group of us went to Las Vegas
الصورة العليا عندما ذهبت مجموعة منا إلى لاس فيجاس.
to compete in a test,
للتنافس على اختبار،
to see if we could match the German troops' physical training standards.
لنرى إذا كنا نستطيع مطابقة معايير التدريب البدني للقوات الألمانية.
It involved swimming, timed sprints, marksmanship and numerous fitness events.
تضمنت سباحة وسباقات العدو الموقوتة والرماية والعديد من أنشطة اللياقة البدنية.
I passed them and satisfied the requirements
اجتزتهم ووفيت بالمتطلبات،
to be awarded the gold German Armed Forces Proficiency Badge right here.
حتى تسلمت شارة الكفاءة الذهبي للقوات المسلحة الألمانية هنا.
This is one of the sergeants, Sergeant Richardson.
هذا أحد الرقباء، الرقيب ريتشاردسون.
I love this guy. He doesn't take baloney from any of us cadets.
أحب هذا الرجل. إنه لا يسخر من أي منا.
Here I am one morning,
هذا أنا في صباح ذات يوم،
when we trekked seven and a half miles with a 40-pound rucksack
عندما قطعنا مسافة سبعة أميال ونصف حاملين حقيبة ظهر وزنها 40 رطلا
in less than two hours.
في أقل من ساعتين.
Here are a few of my fellow cadets.
وهنا بعض زملائي الطلاب.
I've been with them long enough that I’ve developed name signs for them.
أمضيت معهم فترة طويلة كفيلة بأن أخلق لهم أسماء بلغة الإشارة.
On the right, here, is Trinidad.
على اليمين، هنا، ترينيداد.
I gave him this name sign because he's always very sarcastic.
أعطيته هذه الإشارة كناية عن اسمه لأنه دومًا ساخر جدًا.
He's a veteran, having served in Iraq and Afghanistan.
هو محارب مخضرم، قد خدم في العراق وأفغانستان
The female is Frigo, whose nickname is "Refrigerator,"
هذه السيدة فريجو، ولقبها "ثلاجة"
hence her name sign.
وبالتالي إشارة اسمها.
We’re always competing intellectually in class.
كان بيننا منافسة فكرية في الفصل.
The cadet on the end is Jarvy. He's a top athlete.
الطالب في النهاية هو جارفي. هو الرياضي الأمهر.
I've given him this sign because of the scar he has here.
أعطيته هذ الإشارة لأن لديه ندبة هنا.
Do you know who this is?
هل تعرفون من هذا؟
This is the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.
إنه رئيس هيئة الأركان المشتركة.
He is the highest-ranking military officer
إنه الضابط العسكري الأعلى رتبة.
and principal military advisor to President Obama
والمستشار العسكري الأول للرئيس أوباما
and Secretary of Defense Gates.
ووزير الدفاع جيتس.
He gave a talk at UCLA to a full house.
ألقى خطابًا في جامعة كاليفورنيا في لوس أنجلوس لمكانٍ مكتظ بالجمهور
Afterwards, I lined up to shake his hand.
ووقفتُ بعدها في الصف لمصافحته.
Having done so, I greeted him, “It’s a great pleasure to meet you.”
صافحته ورحبتُ به قائلًا، "أنه من دواعي سروري أن ألقاك".
I signed and my interpreter voiced for me.
قلتها بلغة الإشارة وفسرها مترجمي.
Admiral Mullen turned to the interpreter and said, “It’s nice to meet you,”
استدار الأميرال مولان للمترجم وقال، "من الجميل أن ألقاك"
addressing the interpreter, who refrained to clarify.
مخاطبا المترجم، الذي امتنع عن التوضيح.
He seemed a little confused and just quickly moved on
بدى مرتبكًا قليلًا ومضى مسرعًا
to shake hands with the rest of the soldiers.
لمصافحة باقي الجنود.
So I’m not sure whether he really knew that I'm deaf or not.
لذلك لست متأكدًا إذا عرف حقًا أنني أصم أو لا.
So everything’s been moving along, gung-ho, full speed ahead,
كانت الأمور تسيرُ إلى الأمام بحماس، وبأقصى سرعتها قدمًا،
until two weeks ago,
حتى قبل أسبوعين،
when something occurred.
عندما حدث شيء ما.
Well, the ROTC has four levels.
حسنا، لدى هيئة تدريب ضباط الاحتياط أربعة مستويات.
I’m currently doing the first two levels, which finishes up this May.
أقوم حاليًا بأول مستويين، الذين ينتهيان في شهر أيار/مايو.
The third level will begin in the fall.
سيبدا المستوي الثالث هذا الخريف.
But in order to move up, you need to pass a medical exam.
لكن للمضي قدمًا، أحتاجُ لاجتياز فحص طبي.
Obviously, I’m deaf, so I’d fail a hearing test.
من الواضح أنني أصم، لذلك سأرسب في فحص السمع.
So we sat down,
لذلك جلسنا معا،
and I was told that if I wanted to continue to the third level,
وأخبرت أنه إذا أردتُ الاستمرار إلى المستوى الثالث،
I couldn’t do any of the PT workouts in the morning,
لا يمكني أداء أي من التدريبات البدنية الصباحية
nor the Friday lab field trainings, nor the army base trainings.
ولا تدريبات المختبر الميدانية أيام الجمعة ولا تدريبات القاعدة العسكرية.
My uniform, I would have to give back as well.
وينبغي عليّ إرجاع زيي العسكري كذلك.
I could take the classes, audit them, and that’s all.
يمكني حضور الفصول وتدقيقها وهذا كل شيء.
It really hit me. It was a huge blow.
لقد صدمتني حقًا. كانت ضربة قوية.
Many of the officers and cadets have empathized
تعاطف الكثير من الضباط والطلاب العسكريين
with this sudden shock of disappointment,
مع هذه الصدمة المفاجأة من خيبة الأمل،
and are wondering why this has to be the case.
متسائلين لمَ ينبغي أن ينتهي الأمر على هذا النحو؟
Colonel Phelps has tried to speak with the higher-ups
حاول العقيد فيليبس أن يتحدث مع الرؤساء
in the chain of command
في سلسلة القيادة
and explain to them that I’m one of the top cadets,
موضحا لهم أني أحد أفضل الطلاب،
having passed all the events and receiving high marks on my exams.
واجتزت كل الأنشطة والاختبارات وحصلت على الدرجات العليا في الاختبارات.
But their response is unwavering:
لكن ردهم لا يتغير:
policy is policy, and if you’re deaf, you’re disqualified.
القوانين هي السياسة، إذا كنت أصم فهذا يعني أنك غير مؤهل.
I know that the cadre has tried to find various ways.
أعلم أن الكادر حاول إيجاد طرق مختلفة.
They found out that there's a deaf cadet at The Citadel,
وجدوا طالبًا أصم في سيتدال (The Citadal)،
a military college in South Carolina.
الكلية العسكرية في كارولينا الجنوبية.
That particular cadet will be completing his fourth year there
سيكملُ هذا الطالب على وجه الخصوص سنته الرابعة هناك
and graduating this May.
وسيتخرج في أيار/ مايو.
Yet, he's in the same predicament that I'm in --
ومع ذلك فهو في نفس المأزق الذي أنا فيه.
unable to join the army because he’s deaf.
غير قادر على الالتحاق بالجيش كونه أصم.
Yet, all of my fellow cadets and the officers have told me
ومع ذلك أخبرني زملائي الطلاب والضباط
not to give up; the policy must change.
ألا أيأس، يجب أن تتغير السياسة.
I was advised to talk with my congressman.
نُصحت أن أتحدث مع عضو الكونجرس لولايتي.
And I've brought this issue to Henry Waxman,
ورفعت هذه القضية لهنري واكسمان،
the district congressman here in LA,
عضو الكونجرس لمنطقتي هنا في لوس أنجلوس،
to get the ball rolling with his advocacy for my cause.
لكي يبدأ بإتخاذ الإجراءات مع تأييده لقضيتي.
However, I need your help and support to lobby.
مع ذلك، أحتاج مساعدتكم ودعكم لكسب التأييد.
All of us, you know?
جميعنا، أتعرفون؟
If you remember back in US history, African-Americans were told
لو تذكرون فيما مضي في التاريخ الأمريكي، قيل للأمريكان من أصل أفريقي
they couldn’t join the military,
أنهم لا يمكنهم الالتحقاق بالجيش،
and now they serve.
وهم يخدمون الآن.
Women as well were banned, but now they've been allowed.
مُنع النساء كذلك، وسمح لهن الآن.
The military has and is changing.
قد تغير ويتغير الجيش.
Today is our time. Now it’s our turn.
حان وقتنا اليوم. إنه دورنا الآن.
Hooah!
هيا!
(Applause)
(تصفيق)